MATEUS M. FURQUIM MENDONÇA

Machine Learning and Software Engineer

@mfurquimdev@gmail.com

git mfurquimdev

in/mfurquimdev

@mfurquim.dev

Brazil

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled software engineer with over 9 years of experience and a diverse background. Committed to team growth and innovation through effective mentoring and collaboration. Strong problem-solving skills with a passion for delivering high-quality software solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Back-end Developer

📋 Jan 2021 - Present

DevGrid

United Kingdom (Remote)

Managed several microservices that employ machine learning algorithms to estimate house appliances' energy consumption.

- > Achieved up to 59% improvement in **Python** write operations on **Cassandra** through the safe utilization of unlogged batches.
- > Iteratively improved domain models following **Domain Driven Design** approach, increasing efficiency in delivering new features.

Embedded Software Developer

Autotrac

Prasilia, DF - Brazil

Maintained security and logistic features of an embedded system for a customized hardware and Linux kernel.

- > Employed dependency injection and other SOLID principles to enhance C++ code quality and maintainability.
- > Implemented monitoring solutions to gather real-time performance data, ensuring optimal system efficiency and responsiveness.

DevOps Consultant

IBM

🗂 Jan 2019 - Nov 2019

Prasilia, DF - Brazil

Collaborated with multiple teams to improve observability of the back-end services of a prominent banking institution.

- > Contributed to self-discovering services feature using etcd key-value store, consistent hashing and a federation of Prometheus.
- > Employed PromQL to develop alerts that detected low performance of new deployments and potential DDoS attacks.

INTERN EXPERIENCE

EDUCATION

Machine Learning DevOps Engineer

Udacity

Online

BEng. Software Engineering

Universidade de Brasilia (UnB)

🤋 Brasilia, DF - Brazil 👚 Mar 2011 – Jul 2017

University of Victoria (UVic)

Victoria, BC - Canada 📋 Jan 2014 – Apr 2015

LANGUAGES

 ▶ Portuguese
 Mother Tongue

 ▶ English
 Fluent

</> Python Working Knowledge
</> C/C++ Working Knowledge

Go Intermediate Knowledge

Rust Basic Knowledge